

# CONTACT

- +39 340 9310 562
- ★ federico.decillia@gmail.com
- Via Moneta 50, Milan (IT)
- live:federico.decillia
- federicodecillia.github.io

## **EDUCATION**

### M.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS

University of Padova (2012 - 2014)

### **B.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS**

University of Padova (2008 - 2011)

### LLP ERASMUS (BARCELONA)

University Pompeu Fabra (2012)

#### ICT HIGH-SCHOOL DIPLOMA

I.T.I. Severi, Padua (2003 - 2008)

## **EXPERTISE**

Python, R	••••
Git	••••
Office, GSuite, iWork	••••
BI (Tableau, Spotfire)	••••
SQL	••••
SAS, SPSS	••••
KNime	••••
Microsoft Azure	••••
DevOps, CI/CD	••••
AWS, GCP	••••
Docker	••000
Airflow	••000

# FEDERICO DE CILLIA

Lead Data Scientist - R&D, Retail, Market Analysis, Media

## **ABOUT ME**

Senior Data Scientist specialized in Big-Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Time Series modeling, Automation & RPA, BI & Data Visualization, Cloud Computing.

Demonstrated history of strong innovation attitude, leading the change of international Data Science organizations to new tools and methodologies.

Proven track record of leading strategic analytics projects, from ideation to production of ML pipelines, RPA & BI solutions, using programming languages (Python, R, SQL), Data Visualization tools (MS Power BI, Spotfire, Google Data Studio, Tableau, SAS VA), Cloud solutions (Azure, AWS, GCP), exploiting Agile & Software development tools (Git, Azure DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Scrum, Kanban).

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Lead Data Scientist - Retail Optimization, Luxottica** | 02/2021 - present Leading various Big-Data, Automation & Machine Learning Projects for the Global Retail Assortment Intelligence Team

### Senior Data Scientist, Nielsen | 09/2017 - 02/2021

Lead many international projects (with up to 10 people per project) to implement scalable, automated Machine Learning (Classification, Regression, Clustering, Time Series) in multiple countries. Direct exposure to management & clients presenting business insights & analyses. Chair of Italian Diversity & Inclusion Team

**Data Scientist Consultant, Bip (@ Sky Italy)** | 04/2016 - 09/2017 Developed and implemented a NLP Churn-Prediction project & Text-Mining analyses, used to improve Retention/Upselling/Downgrade Marketing strategies.

Data Science Business Consultant, Value Lab | 09/2015 - 04/2016

SAS Masterclass Big Data, SAS Institute | 06/2015 - 09/2015

Data Mining Junior, Bocconi Alumni Association | 02/2015 - 06/2015

Tutor for exchange students, University of Padua | 2012 - 2014

### LANGUAGE SKILLS ATTITUDES & INTERESTS

Italian: Mother tongue	Driver of Innovation, Leader of change
English: Proficient (C1)	Communicator with Storytelling skill
<b>Spanish</b> : Upper-Intermediate (B2)	D&I and Sustainability advocate

# **COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

Azure Data Scientist Associate (DP-100), Microsoft Certification	01/2022
Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900), Microsoft Certification	09/2021
Al for everyone, Deeplearning.ai. on Coursera	12/2020
Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington	01/2020
Deep Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai. on Coursera	06/2019
Complete Git & Github Masterclass, O'Reilly	10/2018
Data Science and ML with Python and Spark, O'Reilly	06/2018
Python for Data Science, University of California San Diego	12/2017
Intro & Intermediate Python for Data Science, Datacamp	09/2017
Text Mining and Analytics, University of Illinois	05/2017
ML for Data Science and Analytics, Columbia University	01/2017
Tackling the challenges of Big Data, MIT	09/2016
SAS Programming - Macro Language - SQL, SAS Institute	09/2015